He's fast. They're furious.
Turbo is a animation, family film directed by David Soren.
The tale of an ordinary garden snail who dreams of winning the Indy 500.
Turbo (voice), played by Ryan Reynolds.
Chet (voice), played by Paul Giamatti.
Tito (voice), played by Michael Peña.
Whiplash (voice), played by Samuel L. Jackson.
Angelo (voice), played by Luis Guzmán.
Guy Gagné (voice), played by Bill Hader.
Turbo is a 2013 American animated sports comedy film directed by David
Soren and written by Soren, Darren Lemke and Robert Siegel.
It stars Ryan Reynolds, Paul Giamatti, Michael Peña, Snoop Dogg,
Maya Rudolph, Michelle Rodriguez, and Samuel L.
In the film, a garden snail pursues his dream of winning the
Indianapolis 500 after a freak accident gives him super speed.
In 2009, DreamWorks Animation organized a competition for its
staff to submit a one-page pitch for film ideas.
Soren's concept was "The Fast and the Furious with
snails" and he won the competition.
With no further development for several years, Soren pushed the project again after he
and his family moved into a new home with a backyard infested with snails.
For the racing elements of the film, Soren was inspired
by his son's fascination with race cars.
Turbo premiered at CineEurope on May 20, 2013, and was theatrically released
in the United States on July 17, 2013, by 20th Century Fox.
It received mixed reviews from critics.
Despite earning $282 million on a $127 million budget, the film was a box
office disappointment, and lost the studio $13.5 million.
A television series based on the film, Turbo Fast, was released in 2013.
The film explores themes of underdog, dreams, car race, sports, speed.